<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the protector. A proclamation commanding all persons, who have been of the late Kings party, or his sons, to depart out of the cities of London and Westminster and late lines of communication, on or before Thursday the twelfth day of July instant.</title>
            <title>Proclamations. 1655-07-06</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Lord Protector (1653-1658 : O. Cromwell)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1655</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A80974</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing C7141</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R231873</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99897631</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99897631</idno>
            <idno type="VID">137270</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A80974)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 137270)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2510:14)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the protector. A proclamation commanding all persons, who have been of the late Kings party, or his sons, to depart out of the cities of London and Westminster and late lines of communication, on or before Thursday the twelfth day of July instant.</title>
                  <title>Proclamations. 1655-07-06</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Lord Protector (1653-1658 : O. Cromwell)</author>
                  <author>Cromwell, Oliver, 1599-1658.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>2 sheets (versos blank)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed by Henry Hills and John Field, printers to His Highness,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>MDCLV. [1655]]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Dated at end: Given at White-hall this 6th day of July, 1655.</note>
                  <note>Arms 51. Steele notation: persons such 2) Appre- these.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Folger Shakespeare Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Commonwealth and Protectorate, 1649-1660 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-09</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:137270:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <head>O P</head>
                  <figDesc>seal of the Commonwealth</figDesc>
               </figure>
               <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> By the Protector. A PROCLAMATION Commanding all perſons, who have been of the late Kings party, or his Sons, to depart out of the Cities of <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> and late Lines of Communication, on or before <hi>Thurſday</hi> the twelfth day of <hi>July</hi> inſtant.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">H</seg>Is Highneſs taking notice of the great confluence and reſort of divers ill-affected perſons (who have born arms againſt the Commonwealth, and otherwiſe adhered to the Enemy, in the late Wars) unto the Cities of <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> and the parts adjacent, and are now lurking in and about the ſame; and having of late received certain intelligence of Deſigns now in hand, endeavored to be carried on by correſpondencies with the Sons of the late King, their Agents, and Complices, againſt the Commonwealth and preſent Government (the Contrivers of which Plots may, for the better effecting the ſame, and with much more eaſe, make uſe of ſuch dangerous and diſcontented perſons now remain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in &amp; about the ſaid Cities) doth (by and with the advice of his Council) for preventing ſuch diſturbances as may thereby ariſe in the future, think fit, and hereby publiſh, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clare, and enjoin, That all perſons who have been at any time in Arms againſt the Commonwealth, or have ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hered unto, or willingly aſsiſted the Enemies thereof, in the time of the late Wars, being within the Cities of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> and <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> or the late Lines of Communication, and not under Reſtraint, nor hereafter excepted, ſhall on or before the twelfth day of <hi>July</hi> inſtant (or if then under Reſtraint) within five daies next after their reſpective In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>largement, depart out of the ſaid Cities of <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> and late Lines of Communication, and all other Places within twenty Miles of the ſaid late Lines, unleſs it be their places of Habitation for themſelves and Families. And if any ſuch perſon or perſons ſhall continue within the ſaid late Lines, or the ſaid diſtance of twenty Miles from the hid Lines, after the ſaid twelfth day of <hi>Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly</hi> inſtant, or if then under Reſtraint, ſhall continue within the Diſtance aforeſaid, above five Dayes
<pb facs="tcp:137270:2" rendition="simple:additions"/> after his or their Inlargement, or ſhall return without Licence, then and in ſuch caſe, he and they ſhall be Appre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hended, Impriſoned and otherwiſe proceeded againſt as Diſturbers of the Peace, and Contemners of Authority. And His Highneſs doth Command the Lord Major and Aldermen of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and all Iuſtices of Peace within the ſaid City, and late Lines of Communication, and of the ſeveral Counties of <hi>Middleſex, Hertford, Eſſex, Kent</hi> and <hi>Surrey,</hi> and the reſpective Committees and Commiſsioners of, and for the <hi>Militia,</hi> within the ſaid City and Liberties, the City of <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> Borough of <hi>Southwa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>k,</hi> Hamlets of the <hi>Tower,</hi> and Suburbs, or any two or more of them in their reſpective Liberties and Iuriſdict<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ons, to cauſe ſtrict Wards and Watches to be kept, and to make frequent Searches for, and apprehend, or cauſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> to be apprehended all ſuch perſons as aforeſaid, which ſhall be found within the Diſtance aforeſaid, after the ſaid Twelfth day of <hi>July</hi> next enſuing; And of their doings therein, under their Hands and Seals in writing, fo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>thwith to certifie His Highneſs Council, to the end the ſaid Offenders may be dealt withal and proceeded again<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>t as Diſturbers of the Peace, and Contemners of Authority; And all Sheriffs, Bayliffs, Conſtables, and all Captains of Guards, Officers and Soldiers, and other the Good People of this Commonwealth, are Required to be Ayding to the ſaid Iuſtices of Peace, Committees and Commiſsioners, their Agents, Officers and Miniſters, in the due and ſpeedy Execution of His Highneſs Commands in the Premiſes. And for the better diſc<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>very, preventing and avoiding of Plots and Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſturbances, dangerous to the Peace of the Commonwealth, H<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>s Highneſs doth ſtraitly Charge and Command, That all the ſaid Perſons appointed to depart as aforeſaid, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ot reſtrained or ſtayed, either by Impriſonment, or ſuch Sickneſs and Infirmity of Body, as they ſhall not be <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>le to travel without imminent Danger of Life, repair to their place of Dwelling, or where they uſually made t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>eir common Aboad, or (not having any certain Aboad) to the place of their Birth, or where their Parents ſhal<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>e then dwelling, and give notice of their coming thither, and preſent themſelves and deliver their true Names <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> writing, to the Miniſter of the Pariſh, and to the Conſtable, Headborough or Tything-man of the Town, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>o ſhall thereupon preſently Enter the ſame into a Book, to be kept in every Pariſh for that purpoſe; And the ſai<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Miniſter, Conſtable, Headborough or Tything-man, are hereby commanded to certifie the ſame in writing to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>e Iuſtices of the Peace of the ſame County, at the next General, or Quarter Seſsions of the Peace, to be held or the ſame County, there to be Entred by the Clerk of the Peace upon the Rolls of the ſame Seſsion upon <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ecord. And it is further Declared, That theſe Preſents ſhall continue in force until the Twentieth day of <hi>Oct<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>er</hi> next enſuing, and no longer.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Given at WHITE-HALL</hi> 
                  <date>
                     <hi>this 6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of July, 1655.</hi>
                  </date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>
                  <hi>Publiſhed by His Highne<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>ecial Command.</hi>
               </signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON:</hi> Printed by <hi>Henry Hills</hi> and <hi>John Field,</hi> Pr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ers to His Highneſs. MDCLV.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
